这是二零二零年福建省初中学业水平考试英语科听力部分。该部分共三节。注意：回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。听力部分结束前，你将有两分。分钟的时间，将你的答案填涂到答题卡上。现在是听力试音时间，请各考场根据试音。情况将音量调到最佳状态。
试音到此结束。听力考试正式开始。请看听力部分第一节。第一节，听句子。听下面五个句子，从每小题所给的三幅图中选出。与句子内容相符的选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。听完每个句子后，你都有五秒钟的时间作答和阅读下一小题。每个句子读两遍。现在你有五秒钟的时间阅。读第一小题的有关内容。一。
Her father used to be a doctor.
Tom has gone to the market with his younger sister.
4. It's polite to get on the bus, one by one.
5. They were flying a kite when I got there.
第一节到此结束。第二节，听对话，听下面七段对话，从每小题所给的三个选项中选出正确答案，并标在试卷的相应位置。听完每段对话后，你都有五秒钟的时间回答有关小题，和五秒钟的时间阅读下一小题。每段对话读两遍。听第一段对话，回答第六小题。现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读这一小题。
听第二段对话，回答第七小题。现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读这一小题。
I plan to visit some friends this summer with my parents.
What about you?
I'm going to travel around Hangzhou with my brothers.
听第三段对话。啊，回答第八小题。现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读这一小题。
Come and look at the pictures.
How beautiful! Who drew them?
Michael drew the flowers, Peter drew the birds, and the houses were drawn by
听第四段对话，回答第九小题。现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读这一小题。
听第五段对话，回答第十、十一两个小题。现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
Excuse me, how much does a ticket for Spider -Man cost?
Fifteen dollars. All right.
Two tickets, please.
And what time does the film start?
At eight p.m.
Have fun. Thanks.
You're welcome. Excuse me, how much does a ticket for Spider -Man cost?
Fifteen dollars. All right.
Two tickets, please.
And what time does the film start?
At eight p.m.
Have fun. Thanks.
You're welcome. Good afternoon, Tony.
听第六段对话，回答第十二、十三两个小题。现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
How are you feeling?
I have a headache.
Let me take your temperature.
It is normal.
Do you have a cough or a running nose?
I have a running nose, but I do not have a cough.
Well, Tony, you have a cold.
But don't worry.
I will give you some pills.
Take them three times a day.
What else should I do?
Don't go out for exercise.
Keep away from crowds and wash hands often.
Got it. Thanks.
Good afternoon, Tony.
How are you feeling?
I have a headache.
Let me take your temperature.
It is normal.
Do you have a cough or a running nose?
I have a running nose, but I do not have a cough.
Well, Tony, you have a cold.
But don't worry.
I will give you some pills.
Take them three times a day.
What else should I do?
Don't go out for exercise.
Keep away from crowds and wash hands often.
Got it. Thanks.
听第七段对话，回答第十四、十五两个小题。现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
Bill, can you stop using your phone while having dinner?
I'm just checking the soccer score.
You'd better not spend so much time on your phone.
It's really bad for your eyes.
And it's very dirty to touch the screen when you're eating.
I'm sorry, Mom.
Put away your phone and enjoy your dinner.
Okay. I'm sorry, Mom.
I'm away your phone and enjoy your dinner.
Okay. Good morning, everyone.
第二节到此结束。第三节，听短文。根据你所听到的短文内容，完成下面表格，每空填一词。听短文前，你将有二十秒的时间阅读表格内容。短文读三遍。
Welcome to our online meeting.
I'm now telling you something about your child's final examinations.
The examinations start on July 24th and finish on July 26th.
Your child has received an examination timetable.
It is necessary that your child should arrive at school on time with school things,
such as pencils, a ruler, an eraser, and so on.
It is very important that your child should review lessons at home.
There are many things that you can do to help your child.
For example, provide a quiet space for your child to study.
Make sure that your child gets a good sleep and does not miss breakfast.
Please call your child's class teacher when you have any questions.
Thank you. Good morning, everyone.
Welcome to our online meeting.
I'm now telling you something about your child's final examinations.
The examinations start on July 24th and finish on July 26th.
Your child has received an examination timetable.
It is necessary that your child should arrive at school on time with school things,
such as pencils, a ruler,
an eraser, and so on.
It is very important that your child should review lessons at home.
There are many things that you can do to help your child.
For example, provide a quiet space for your child to study.
Make sure that your child gets a good sleep and does not miss breakfast.
Please call your child's class teacher when you have any questions.
Thank you. Good morning, everyone.
Welcome to our online meeting.
I'm now telling you something about your child's final examinations.
The examinations start on 24th and finish on July 26th.
Your child has received an examination timetable.
It is necessary that your child should arrive at school on time with school things,
such as pencils, a ruler,
an eraser, and so on.
It is very important that your child should review lessons at home.
There are many things that you can do to help your child.
For example, provide a quiet space for your child to study.
Make sure that your child gets a good sleep and does not miss breakfast.
Please call your child's class teacher when you have any questions.
Thank you. You You
第三节到此结束。现在你有两分钟的时间将。试卷上的答案填涂到答题卡上。
You The
听力部分到此结束。